+1 (778) 222-7403 • Vancouver/BC • marcelo.luis.santos@outlook.com

Career Summary

Professional with 10 years of experience in IT area, having obtained a strong background in the entire Software Development Lifecycle by performing the roles of System Analyst and Developer, Software Architect, Team Leader and having collaborated to manage a tech startup company.

Solid experience working with today's best-in-class technologies such as .Net Framework, Asp.Net, C#, WPF, PHP, Flex, Flex Mobile, HTML5, JavaScript, Apache Cordova as well as iOS and Android ecosystems, having delivered remarkable projects in these both mobile platforms. Extensive know-how of largely adopted enterprise databases like SQL Server, MySQL and Oracle.

As Team Leader in a software development company I was responsible for planning, control, delegate and prioritize tasks, being able to define patterns and optimize the company's development process by creating system architectures built upon widely used best practices.

Education

♦ Mobile Application Development 2014 Post-Graduation Degree - UNISINOS, São Leopoldo, Brazil ♦ Systems Information 2012

Bachelor's Degree - Dom Bosco Faculty, Porto Alegre, Brazil

Professional Experience

Connected Interactive – Senior Software Engineer

2017 to 2018

Performance and marketing firm specialized in mobile and desktop advertising.

- Developer of mobile SDK's for native Android, iOS (Objective-C) and Unity 3D (C#), used by more than 30 third party applications.
- Responsible for creating and maintaining the continuous integration environment for mobile platforms.
- Analysis and software development for digital advertising software using PHP, JavaScript (AngularJS and React) and MySQL.

General Electric Global Research – Mobile Software Engineer

2016 to 2017

Research Center of General Electric that develops innovative products for its businesses.

- Researcher and software engineer working specifically with mobile and wearable devices for Android and iOS platforms.
- Development of applications using augmented reality using standard SDK's as Unity3D, for example, and wearable devices.

 Responsible for creating mobile software architectures and project leadership being responsible for planning tasks, deliverables and communication with customers.

Stone Pagamentos – Mobile Developer

2016 to 2016

Payments acquirer to accredit merchants, process and authorize credit card transactions under many card flags.

- Developer of mobile applications for Android and iOS as well as being in charge of designing of architectures for both platforms.
- Responsible for in-company training about software architecture and design patterns using C# language and Visual Studio IDE.

Eco Sistemas – Senior Software Developer / Systems Analyst

2014 to 2016

Major software supplier for the public health sector in Rio de Janeiro.

- Analysis and software development to health sector using .NET and technologies such as HTML5,
 JavaScript, AngularJS, Asp.Net, WCF, WPF, WebAPI's, Android, iOS and Windows Mobile.
- Support in R&D area helping in the definition and implementation of new technologies.
- Leadership and architecture definition on native mobile development technologies, both for Android and iOS and furthermore, to hybrid applications using Apache Cordova framework.

CWI - Mobile – Software Mobile Developer / Systems Analyst

2014 to 2014

IT company which provides global technology services, including Software Factory, Project Factory, Test Factory and Outsourcing.

- Mobile Application Developer to Android and Windows Phone platforms.
- Customer's requirements gathering and task analysis using UML best practices.
- Tasks planning aiming the development of specific software requirements as well as resources and deliverables planning to customers.

♦ BeelT – Partner / Team Leader

2011 to 2014

Outsourcing Startup which develops software to health sector.

- Software Architect and Team Leader having participated in the company management.
- Responsible for company's technical area and led a team of 6 people across 3 projects.
- Development of company frameworks, using mostly backend technologies such as .NET, WCF and ASP.NET besides other frontend technologies like Flex, Flex Mobile, Android and iOS with SQL Server and Oracle databases support.
- Responsible for planning, controlling, managing and delegating tasks as well.

Cia. Salux – Software Developer / Systems Analyst

2007 to 2011

Software developer company for health sector with customers distributed for all country.

- Developer and System Analyst of health sector solutions using .NET, ASP.NET and PL/SQL.
- Requirements gathering with customers, business and technical documentation creation according to the company's standards and UML best practices.
- Technical leadership towards development team.
- Acting in architecture and framework development and deployment of SVN and TFS tools.